Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the 10
Commandments that God had written for
the whole world to keep. Brother James.
Yes, sir.
And God spoke all these words saying, "I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shalt have no
other gods before me. Thou shalt not
make unto thee any graven image or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above or that is in the earth beneath or
that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them
nor serve them, for I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me and showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me and keep
my commandments. Thou shalt not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain. For
the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain.
Remember the Sabbath day to keep it
holy. Six days shalt thou labor and do
all thy work, but the seventh day is the
Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In it thou
shalt not do any work, thou nor thy son
nor thy daughter, thy man servant nor
thy maid servant nor thy cattle nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea and all that in them is
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day and
hallowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee.
Thou shalt not kill. Thou shalt not
commit adultery. Thou shalt not steal.
Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shalt not
covet thy neighbor's house. Thou shalt
not covet thy neighbor's wife nor his
man servant nor his maid servant nor his
ox nor his ass nor anything that is thy
neighbor's. I read Exodus 20:1-17.
May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of this word. In Jesus' name we
pray. Amen.
Amen.
So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague as well as
the long scripture questions and
questions of debate. We're not here to
debate. We're here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also
remember that this is a live stream, so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you please keep them to a
two scripture maximum. But let me
introduce you to the family that's on
the panel this evening. We got Brother
Julius. Good evening, everybody.
We got Brother Dre.
Good evening.
Brother Jerome.
Grace and peace.
Brother James.
Good evening, everyone.
Sister Deborah.
Good evening.
Brother Shawn.
And we have the guest caller with us and
I'm Brother Cornell. Sister Deborah,
what is our first question of the
program?
Yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A. So
Lovely Cole asks, "How can I show
someone
God doesn't love everyone except people
who follow his commandments?"
All right, so how can it be shown to
them that God doesn't love everyone
except people who follow his
commandments? Guest caller.
Yes.
Let's go to Proverbs 8 and read verse
17.
Proverbs 8 and 17, right, James?
Correct, sir.
And Proverbs 8 and 17 says, "I love them
that love me and those that seek me
early shall find me."
Now let's go to St. John the 14th
chapter.
Read verse
21.
Okay, John 14 and verse 21 says,
"He that hath my commandments and
keepeth them, he it is that loveth me.
And he that loveth me shall be loved of
my Father, and I will love him and will
manifest myself to him."
Okay, let's go to St. John the 15th
chapter.
Read verses 8 and 9.
Okay. John 15:8-9
says,
"Herein is my Father glorified that ye
bear much fruit, so shall ye be my
disciples.
As the Father had loved me, so have I
loved you. Continue ye in my love.
Go ahead.
If ye keep my commandments, ye shall
abide in my love even as I have kept my
Father's commandments and abide in his
love."
Verse 10 is right there. If you don't
keep his commandments, you're not going
to abide in his love. That's all I have
to say.
All right.
Thank you for that. We hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next one.
Our next one, Yourself continued his
question from last week and asked,
"Wasn't it the testimony that was placed
in the ark of the covenant?"
All right, placed inside the ark of the
covenant.
Brother Jerome.
Um yeah, there there's a verse in Exodus
31 uh that we're going to go to to show
that. But you
you don't want to confuse the New
Testament being a testimony
of the Old Testament. You don't want to
confuse the two, okay?
But let's go read the verse that states
that the testimony was put in the ark of
the covenant, okay? I got two places I
want to read. Let's go to Deuteronomy 10
verse 1 and 2.
When you get it, go ahead and read.
Deuteronomy 10:1-2
says,
"At that time the Lord said unto me,
hew thee two tables of stone like unto
the first and come up unto me into the
mount and make thee an ark of wood. Mhm.
And I will write on the tables the words
that were in the first tables which thou
breakest, and thou shalt put them in the
ark. So we're talking about the
10 Commandments that was wrote on two
tables of stone, okay? He wanted that to
be put in the ark of the covenant. Now
let's tie that with Exodus 31
and read verse 18.
Okay. [clears throat]
It says, "And he gave unto Moses, when
he had made an end of communing with him
upon Mount Sinai, two tables of
testimony, tables of stone written with
the finger of God." And those two tables
of testimony is the 10 Commandments,
okay?
Like I said earlier, but don't confuse
the
New Testament being a testimony of the
Old Testament. That's that's something
different.
Okay? One more place and then I'll be
done. Let's go to Revelations 19 and
read verse 10 and that'll be it.
Okay.
Revelation 19:10 says,
"And I fell at his feet to worship him,
and he said unto me, see thou do it not.
I am thy fellow servant and of thy
brethren that have the testimony of
Jesus. Worship God, for the testimony of
Jesus is the spirit of prophecy." Yeah,
that's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we continue to move on.
Uh yes, moving on. How soon after death
does one go to heaven?
All right, so after you die,
how soon after that and what happens,
Brother Julius?
Let's go to the Bible. Let's go to
Romans out of Salvation. James, let's go
to Genesis chapter 2
and read one verse and let's see if man
came from heaven.
Genesis 2, and where did God get man
from, the first man Adam? Genesis 2:7.
When you get it, brother, read it.
And the Lord God formed man of the dust
of the ground and breathed into his
nostrils the breath of life, and man
became a living soul.
So the soul is
a body?
And man became a living soul. He formed
man from the dust of the ground, but
then he put air in him in his nostrils
to mobilize him. Now, let's go to the
book of Job. Hold Genesis. Let's go to
the book of Job, the 34th chapter, and
let's reverse the process when a person
die.
Working in the hospital all them years,
I've seen people born, babies born. You
have a birth certificate, and when you
die, they give you a death certificate.
Genesis 34 and read verses 14 and 15.
Now, this is the reverse of what happens
when a person dies. Go ahead.
If he set his heart upon man, if he
gather unto himself his spirit and his
breath,
all flesh shall perish together, and man
shall turn again unto dust. No, you go
to heaven.
Shall turn again unto dust. That's why
you say ashes to ashes and dust to dust.
So now, let's go back to Genesis, and
then I got one place after this one.
Back to Genesis, the third chapter.
Let's confirm that. Genesis 3, and this
is man's punishment. Wages of sin is
death, that's the first death, and then
the second death also, which is the lake
of fire, but this the one where
everybody go when you pass. Genesis
3:19, go ahead.
In the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat
bread, till thou return unto the ground.
Until you go back to heaven.
Till thou return unto the ground.
Go ahead. For out of it was thou taken,
for dust thou art, and unto dust shalt
thou return. Because you didn't come
from heaven, so you don't go to heaven.
So now,
let's go to St. John the third chapter.
St. John 3, and Jesus going to ask a
question, and then he's going to give
you an answer. Genesis John 3,
verses 12 and 13. And I don't understand
how the world don't understand this. Go
ahead.
If I have told you earthly things, and
you believe not, how shall you believe
if I tell you of heavenly things? If I
tell you about
earthly things, things you could hear,
see, smell, taste, touch, and you don't
understand them, how shall you believe
if I tell you of heavenly or spiritual
things? And what else?
And no man hath ascended up to heaven,
but he that came down from heaven, even
the Son of man, which is in heaven.
Now, this is the Lord. If you got a
red-letter Bible, this is Jesus
speaking. No man has ascended up in the
heaven,
except he that came down. That's why he
had to go and sit back on the right hand
of the Father, cuz he came from heaven.
But when you die, you go down back to
the dust, sisters and brothers. So now,
somebody say, "Well, brother Julius,
Elijah went to heaven." Yeah, but which
one? There's three heavens.
Every time a tornado comes out the
clouds, it come out of heaven. Another
word for that is called a firmament. So
therefore, Jesus told you,
and he had Moses write it.
You You got You come from the ground,
you go back to the ground, and the only
thing that go back to God is the breath.
Sisters and brothers, so you don't go to
heaven, you go to the ground until a
resurrection. He told you in St. John 6
chapter four times, "I'mma raise you up
at the last day."
So everybody that ever lived and died is
in the grave until a resurrection.
That's all I got.
All right.
Thank you for that, brother. Hopefully
that answered their question. Our next
question.
Uh yes, can you explain 2
Peter 2:9?
2 Peter 2:9. Let's go there, brother
James.
2 Peter 2:9.
And go ahead and read it when you get
there, brother.
It says, "The Lord knoweth how to
deliver the godly out of temptations,
and to reserve the unjust until the day
of judgment to be punished."
Yeah, so the Lord knoweth how to deliver
the godly out of temptation. The ones
that are serving him, he know how to
deliver them out, and he also know how
to reserve the unjust, the ones that's
not serving him, until the day of
judgment to be punished.
Let's go into Psalms, the 34th chapter.
Psalms 34.
Cuz the Lord is always reminding us
that, "Hey,
he got the righteous back one way or
another."
Psalms 34, and let's pick it up at that
verse 15. Psalms 34 and verse 15, and
we're going to bring some just and
unjust
into
this verse. Go ahead.
The eyes of the Lord are upon the
righteous, and his ears are open unto
their cry. Yep.
The face of the Lord
is against them that do evil, to cut off
the remembrance of them from the earth.
So we talking about the righteous here.
Lord is open unto their cry, but the
evil,
he going to cut off the remembrance of
them, like we read about the ungodly in
that
2 Peter 2:9. Go ahead, brother.
The righteous cry, and the Lord heareth,
and delivereth them out of all their
troubles. Oh, that's why he say he know
how to deliver the righteous. Go ahead.
The Lord is nigh unto them that are of a
broken heart, and saveth such as be of a
contrite spirit. One more verse.
Many are the afflictions of the
righteous, but the Lord delivereth them
out of them all.
So that's why the Lord talks about again
how he can deliver us at any time. Now,
I'm going to come back to Psalms 1.
Psalms, the first chapter.
And we're going to read that verse 1 and
2, and then we go skip.
Psalms 1,
and read that verse
1 and 2, brother, so we can see
about the ones that are ungodly as well.
Go ahead.
Blessed is the man that walketh not in
the counsel of the ungodly, nor standeth
in the way of sinners, nor sitteth in
the seat of the scornful.
Who is his delight in? Go ahead.
>> But But his delight is in the law of the
Lord, and in his law doth he meditate
day and night. Or keeping that law would
do you a great service to yourself. Skip
down and read verse 4.
The ungodly are not so,
but are like the chaff which the wind
driveth away.
Yep, don't let your time clock run out
on being ungodly. Go ahead.
Therefore, the ungodly shall not stand
in the judgment, nor sinners in the
congregation of the righteous.
For the Lord knoweth the way of the
righteous, but the way of the ungodly
shall perish.
So when the Lord say he know how to
deliver the godly, and he know how to
destroy the ungodly, hey,
he's got our back, and if you walk with
him, you won't regret it. That's all I
got.
All right, we're going to keep it
moving, sister Deborah, straight through
our next question.
Yes, next one. Tradition of man are to
celebrate Christmas, Easter, Valentine's
Day, Halloween,
and other holidays. Does God have
holidays we should celebrate?
All right, so tradition of man celebrate
all these Christmas, Easter, Valentine's
Day, Halloween, etc.
Yes, caller.
Yeah, well, God have holy days.
And all of them are written
in the 23rd chapter of Leviticus.
Go to the 23rd chapter of Leviticus and
I'm there.
Do we start at verse 1?
Yeah.
Okay.
Leviticus 23:1 says, "And the Lord spake
unto Moses, saying, 'Speak unto the
children of Israel, and say unto them
concerning the feast of the Lord,
which ye shall proclaim to be holy
convocations, even these are my feast.'"
Okay, so he go on and name them.
He got the
uh
memorial, the Passover the
Passover.
Then you got the first and last day of
the feast of unleavened bread.
Yep. Then you have feast of Pentecost.
Mhm. Then you have the memorial of the
blowing of the trumpets.
You have the
uh
feast of uh
You know, the day of atonement.
Then you have the feast
of tabernacle,
and you have the eighth day, and we keep
them all.
So
those are holy days.
That's all I have to say.
All right.
So we hope that answered your question.
And we're going to keep on moving on to
our next one.
Yeah. So, if a husband and wife are
alive at the time Jesus returns and they
meet the Lord in the air, are they still
husband and wife?
All right.
A married couple, they meet the Lord in
the air, are they still a married
couple, Brother Jerome?
Well,
they're going to be spirit beings
um at the resurrection
especially this uh the first
resurrection. And their marriage, while
they were flesh and blood
beings, you know, it it's going to be
like an afterthought, you know.
It's not going to be an issue those that
come up in that first resurrection.
They're going They're going to be God.
Okay? That's the purpose of the Lord
creating this flesh and blood man, to
make him just like himself. Okay? But
let's go to Luke chapter 20.
And we're going to pick it up at verse
29. We're going to read it all the way
to 36.
Let me get it. Go ahead and read.
Luke 21 and verse 29 says
And he spake to them a parable. Behold
the fig tree and all the trees.
Yeah. Okay.
Exodus 20 and 29.
Oh, I'm sorry. Not Exodus. I'm sorry.
Luke 20 and 29. Correct? Yeah. Okay.
There were therefore seven brethren. And
the first took a wife and died without
children.
And the second took her to wife and he
died childless. And the third took her
and in like manner the seven also. And
they left no children and died.
Last of all, the woman died also.
Therefore, in the resurrection, whose
wife of them is she? For seven had her
to wife.
And Jesus answering said unto them, "The
children of this world marry and are
given in marriage. But they which shall
be accounted worthy to obtain that world
and the resurrection from the dead
neither marry nor are given in marriage.
Neither can they die anymore, for they
are equal unto the angels and are the
children of God, being the children of
the resurrection."
They equal unto the angels, meaning that
they can't die.
They're going to have a body that can't
die, that's going to live forever. Okay?
And they're going to be the children of
God, being the children of the
resurrection. Okay? So, let's tie that
with
um
Philippians chapter 3.
And we're going to read verse 20 through
21.
That'll be it.
Philippians 3 and 20 through 21
says
says, "For our conversation is in
heaven. From whence also we look for our
for the savior, the Lord Jesus Christ,
who shall change our vile body that it
may be fashioned like unto his glorious
body, according to the working whereby
he is able even to subdue all things
under himself."
Yeah, so you're going to have body just
like your Lord and savior
and the marriage that you had when you
was flesh and blood, that's not even
going to be an issue. Okay? Right.
That's all I got on it.
Yes, sir.
>> in short, no, there will be no husband
and wife.
All right.
Looking forward to that change, to that
vile body. All right.
We're going to move on to our next
question.
Next one. In Genesis 32 verses 24
through 30, did Jacob wrestle with a man
or God?
All right. Genesis 32
24 through 30. Dre, so
who was wrestling who here?
Let's go read it. Let's go read Genesis
32 24 to 30. Go ahead when you get
there, James.
Okay. It says "And Jacob was left alone.
And there wrestled a man with him unto
the breaking of the day.
And when he saw that he prevailed not
against him, he touched the hollow of
his thigh. And the hollow of Jacob's
thigh was out of joint as he wrestled
with him.
And he said, "Let me go, for the day
breaketh." And he said, "I will not let
thee go, except thou bless me."
And he said unto him, "What is thy
name?" And he said, "Jacob." And he
said, "Thou name shall Thy Thy name
shall be called no more Jacob, but
Israel.
For as a prince has thou power with God
and with men and has prevailed."
And Jacob asked him and said, "Tell me,
I pray thee, thy name." And he said,
"Wherefore is it that thou dost ask
after my name?" And he blessed him
there. And Jacob called the name of this
place Peniel, "for I have seen God face
to face and my life is preserved."
So, in verse 24, it said Jacob was left
alone and there wrestled a man
with him until the breaking of the day.
And
uh then in verse 30, it says
Jacob called the name of the place
Peniel
"for I have seen God face to face
and my life is pre- preserved."
So, now let's go let's go bring some
clarity to it. Let's go to Hebrews 13
and read verse 2.
Hebrews 13 and 2.
Read that when you get there.
Hebrews 13 and 2 says
"Be not forgetful to entertain
strangers, for thereby some have
entertained angels unawares." So, so you
can entertain an angel unaware, but
let's see. Let's make sure that this is
what this is.
Now, let's go to Hosea 12.
Read verses 3 and 4. Hosea 12 3 and 4.
When you get there, go ahead, brother.
Hosea 12 verses
3 and 4 says
says, "He took his brother by the heel
in the womb and by his strength he had
power with God." So, this is talking
about Jacob. He grabbed the heel of his
brother Esau
and he had strength
he had and by his strength he had power
with God. Go ahead, verse 4.
Yea, he had power over the angel and
prevailed. He wept and made supplication
unto him. He found him in Bethel and
there he spake with us. Okay, there you
go. He had power with God and he had and
yea, he had power over the angel. So,
that was an angel [clears throat]
that he dealt with. It wasn't a man
and it wasn't God, but let's go to one
last place. Let's go to Exodus 23. Read
verse
20 and 21.
Exodus 23 and verses 20 and 21 said
says, "Behold, I send an angel before
thee to keep thee in the way
and to bring
Beware of him and obey his voice.
Provoke him not, for he will not pardon
your transgressions, for my name is in
him."
So, the angel is coming in the name of
the Lord.
So
that was an angel that he dealt with
there.
That's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we continue to move on.
Uh moving on. Does IOG believe in or
teach speaking in tongues?
Speaking in tongues. Brother Julius.
Yes, IOG believes in tongues. But in
terms of teaching speaking in tongues,
no.
Let's find out what tongues are. Let's
go to Genesis the 10th chapter.
Genesis chapter 10.
Bear with me a little bit on this one
right here. We got the scriptures to hit
real quick. Genesis 10.
And let's pick this up at verse 1 and
then we're going to skip to 5, James.
Okay. This is everybody All of these are
the sons of Noah. Everybody that you see
in the world today is one of come out of
one of these sons. Go ahead.
Now, these are the generations of the
sons of Noah.
Shem, Ham, and Japheth. And unto them
were sons born after the flood.
So, then it gives you the the nations of
what they exist, the Gentiles first.
Verse 5.
By these were the isles of the Gentiles
divided in their lands. Everyone after
his tongue Everyone after his language.
Uh-huh.
after their families in their nations.
Skip down. Skip down, my brother, to the
sons of Ham.
Read verse
uh 20.
These are the sons of Ham, after their
families, after their tongues, in their
countries and in their nations. These
are your African peoples, and these are
the rest of the sons of uh Shem,
your Shemitic people. Skip down to verse
31 and read it.
These are the sons of Shem, after their
families, after their tongues, in their
lands, after their nations. And in 11th
chapter, read verse 1 quick.
And the whole earth was one language and
of one speech. One language and one
speech which is the same as their
tongue.
Same thing. Now, let's go to 1
Corinthians the 14th chapter, what they
call
uh popularly call the tongue
chapter.
Because it's better to prophesy than to
speak in tongue.
What they called what the world called
tongues is uh uh
when they get up into it's all kind of
different languages and babblings that
nobody understand what they saying.
Pick it up at verse 4 and 5.
1 Corinthians 14:4 and 5. Go ahead.
He that speaketh in an unknown tongue
edifieth himself, but he that
prophesieth edifieth the church.
So now, when you prophesy, you speaking
language plainly that's understanding,
and the church is educated or edified.
But if you speaking in tongue, and
there'll be no interpreter, everybody
going to say this person is
uh crazy or lunatic. Skip down uh What
verse was that? That was verse 4. Read
verse 5.
Look at what Paul said. This is in the
church now. Go ahead.
I would that ye all spake with tongues,
but rather that ye prophesy. What Paul
said.
For greater is he that prophesieth than
he that speaketh with tongues, except he
interpret that the church may receive
edifying. So if somebody come into the
Israel of God and speaking in Spanish,
we need a Spanish interpreter so that
the church can be edified so that the
message can be brought forth. But if
somebody comes in and there's no
interpreter, who's edified?
That person is speaking, but nobody
understand what they're saying. Either
way it go, it is still language, it is
still tongue. Skip down to verse 9. Go
ahead.
So likewise ye,
except ye utter by the tongue words easy
to be understood, how shall it be known
what is spoken? For ye shall speak into
the air. Because there is no
interpreter. Give me verse 18, brother.
I thank my God
>> Paul Paul is multilingual.
Paul spoke Hebrew. Paul spoke uh spoke
Greek. Paul He spoke many languages.
Look what he said. Go ahead.
I thank my God I speak with tongues more
than ye all.
Cuz he was multilingual. Go ahead.
Yet in the church I had rather speak
five words with my understanding that by
my voice I might teach others also than
10,000 words in an unknown tongue. Oh my
goodness. Give me verse 27 and 28 and
we're done. Go ahead. If any man speak
in an unknown tongue, let it be by two
or at the most by three. And that by
course, and let one interpret. So that
everybody can be edified. Notice
speaking,
tongue, talking. Go ahead.
What? If there be no interpreter, let
him keep silence in the church, and let
him speak to himself and to God. So
therefore, sisters and brothers, the
church has made tongue a mysterious uh
language that nobody understand except
the person that's talking. That is
called glossolalia.
But Paul said I'd rather speak five
words with my understanding than 10,000
because tongue is for
unbelievers, prophesying is for
believers.
So, the Israel of God, we believe in
tongue, which is language, but we don't
teach it. We because there's no
interpreter.
That's all I got.
>> something.
Let me read something here.
Go to
uh Hebrews the second chapter when they
have Pentecost.
Yep.
>> uh
verse 1.
Acts the second chapter.
>> Acts the second chapter.
All right. Acts the second chapter.
Go ahead.
Acts 2 and verse 1 says, And when the
day of Pentecost was fully come, they
were all with one accord in one place.
Go ahead. And suddenly there came a
sound from heaven as of a rushing mighty
wind, and it filled all the house where
they were sitting.
And there appeared unto them cloven
tongues, like as of fire, and it sat
upon each one of them.
And they were filled with the Holy Ghost
and began to speak with other tongues as
the Spirit gave them utterance.
Go ahead. And there was dwelling at
Jerusalem Jews, devout men out of every
nation under heaven.
Now, when there was noise abroad, and
the multitude came together and were
confounded because that every man heard
them speak in his own language.
Go ahead.
>> [clears throat]
>> And they were all amazed and marveled,
saying one to another, Behold, are not
all these speak which speak Galileans?
And how hear we every man in our own
tongue wherein we were born?
So let you know that
uh uh there was fire and tongue to sit
by each one of them, they was
interpreting.
That's why they said
they uh Are not all these people that
speak Galileans? Then why is it that we
hear them speak in our own tongue? But
the Bible also said they spoke by the
Holy Ghost, didn't they? Yes, sir.
>> Read one more.
Saint uh uh
Saint John 6 and 63.
John 6.
John 6 and 63.
Yep. Says,
It is the spirit that quickeneth. The
flesh profiteth nothing. The words that
I speak unto you, they are spirit and
they are life.
So that is the spirit
that give the utterance, the word of
God. That's all I have to say.
All right.
>> get his call. Thank you for that. As we
continue to move on to our next question
with the time check. Yes, the time is
8:11.
Um what does Isaiah 48:12
and 13 mean?
Isaiah 48:12
and verse 13. Let's go there, brother
James.
Okay, I'm there.
And let's pick up that verse 12. Isaiah
and read that verse 12 for me. Go ahead.
Hearken unto me, O Jacob, and Israel my
call. I am he.
I am the first, I also am the last.
Okay, so this is
the one who came and died for the sins
of the whole world, letting us know that
he is the first, Genesis, and he is the
last, all the way to Revelation. But he
said, Hearken unto me, O Jacob and
Israel my call. My call to do what?
Let's go quickly to Matthew 28.
Matthew the 28th chapter.
And this is what Israel was called
to do. Matthew 28, brother. Read that
verse 18 through 20 for me.
This came directly out of Jesus' mouth.
Go ahead, brother.
And Jesus came and spake unto them,
saying, All power is given unto me in
heaven and in earth. Uh-huh. Go ye
therefore, and teach all nations,
baptizing them in the name of the
Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy
Ghost. Uh-huh.
>> See, teaching them to observe all things
whatsoever I have commanded you, and lo,
I am with you always, even unto the end
of the world. Amen. All right. So I just
wanted to show that verse 12 was showing
Paul to do what? Paul to go into all the
nations and teach this word and baptize.
And we are teaching this word right now
to all who are viewing with us. Now, go
back, brother, and let's read that verse
13.
Okay. It says,
>> Isaiah 48:13.
Go ahead. It says, My hand also hath
laid the foundation of the earth, and my
right hand hath spanned the heavens.
When I called unto them, they stand up
together.
Yes, and this is the Lord saying here
that, Hey, his hand created everything.
It's all in Genesis. Tell you he created
the heavens and the moon and the sun and
the stars and all of those good things.
But let's go to uh John.
Let's go to John, brother, the first
chapter. Cuz he said that, hey,
his right hand can span and created all
this. Let's go to John, the first
chapter, and pick it up at that verse 1
when you get there. John 1 and 1. And
here's the Godhead right here, the
Father and the Son.
But this is the Son that's saying he
created all things. Go ahead.
In the beginning was the word, and the
word was with God, and the word was God.
Uh-huh. The same was in the beginning
with God.
All things were made by him, and without
him was not anything made that was made.
Oh, so he letting us know what he mean
when he said he expanded the heavens and
that he created all these things. Go
ahead, brother, cuz if without his hand,
nothing was created. Go ahead. What's
that next verse saying, and that'll be
it. In him was life, and the life was
the light of men.
Yes, and in him was life because he even
breathed life
into the nostrils of man, and man became
a living soul.
So, we see in that verse 12 about call,
call to do what? Go and teach all
nations. And then verse 13, on who
created everything, it was the same one
that came and died for the sins of the
whole world. That's all I got.
All right, we'll go leave it right
there, and we'll go move on to that next
question.
Next one. Who is Benjamin Netanyahu
over in Israel? Isn't he the true Jew?
All right, Benjamin Netanyahu
over in Israel. Is he the true Jew? Yes,
caller.
No.
That's all I have to say.
Oh, okay. All right, one-word answer
there, N-O. All right.
We'll go keep it moving right along.
Uh yes, next question is really
piggybacking on that uh Isaiah 48:12
and 13
uh that we just finished with. Uh the
question is in Colossians 1:15-17.
It is talking about Christ who created
everything, or is this also talking
about God in Genesis 1:1 who created
everything?
All right. So, uh we'll go go to that
book of Colossians there, brother
Jerome.
That book right after Philippians, and
take it from there, brother.
Let's go read it. Colossians 1:15-17.
Okay, it says,
"Who is the image of the invisible God,
the firstborn of every creature.
For by him were all things created that
are in heaven and that are in earth,
visible and invisible, whether they be
thrones or dominions or principalities
or powers. All things were created by
him and for him.
And he is before all things, and by him
all things consist."
And he also gave
um
Genesis 1:1. Let's go read that.
Okay. Genesis 1:1 says,
"In the beginning God created the heaven
and the earth."
Okay. So,
uh as Cornell has stated earlier,
um
the Son is the one that created
everything, but I want to give you one
verse so we can dispel of the confusion
about verses that appear to say that the
Father is creating things, and then you
read other verses that say the Son is
creating everything, okay? Let's go to
Ephesians chapter 3 and read verse 9.
Ephesians 3:9 says,
"And to make all men see what is the
fellowship of the mystery which from the
beginning of the world have been hid in
God who created all things by Jesus
Christ." Yeah, so if you read verses
that
seem like the Father is creating things,
he let you know he sent the Son to do
the to do the creating.
Mhm.
And so, one more place,
um
St. John,
uh no, go to Hebrews 1.
Yeah, Hebrews 1 and read verse 1 through
3, and that'll be it.
Okay. Hebrews 1:1-3
says, "God, who at sundry times and in
diver divers manners spake in time past
unto the fathers by the prophets,
hath in these last days spoken unto us
by his Son,
who he appointed heir of all things, by
whom also he made the worlds."
"Who being the brightness of his glory,
That's good. That's good. That's good.
>> Okay. So, he's saying like the you know,
the Father made everything by the hand
of his Son,
Mhm. Jesus Christ.
Yeah. That's all I got on that.
All right.
>> One more. All power.
Yes, sir, guest caller.
St. John 5:37.
Okay. St. John 5:37 says,
"And the Father himself, which hath sent
me, hath borne witness of me. Ye have
neither heard his voice at any time, nor
seen his shape."
Okay.
All right.
Okay, we hope that that answered your
question now, sister Deborah. Next one.
Uh next one. For what reason can a man
divorce his wife?
I want to divorce my wife. For what
reason would that be, brother Dre?
Let's go over to Matthew, the 19th
chapter.
This question was asked to Jesus,
and let's see what his answer was.
Yep. Matthew 19 and pick it up at verse
3.
Okay.
Matthew 19:3 says, "The Pharisees also
came unto him, tempting him, and saying
unto him,
Is it lawful for a man to put away his
wife for every cause?" So, whatever
cause that come up, I can I put away my
wife? Go ahead.
And he answered and said unto them,
"Have ye not read that he which made
them at the beginning made them male and
female?
And said, For this cause shall a man
leave father and mother, and shall
cleave to his wife, and they shall
twain, and they twain shall be one
flesh.
Wherefore, wherefore they are no more
twain, but one flesh. What therefore God
hath joined together, let no let not man
put asunder." So, marriage, what God
joined together in covenant marriage,
let no man put asunder. Verse 7 through
9. Go ahead.
They said unto him,
"Why did Moses then command to give a
writing of divorcement and to put her
away?"
He said unto them, "Moses, because of
the hardness of your hearts, suffered
you to put away your wives, but from the
beginning it was not so." It wasn't so
from the beginning that you put away
your wives. Go ahead.
"And I say unto you,
whosoever shall put away his wife,
except it be for fornication, and shall
marry another, committeth adultery. And
whosoever marrieth her which is put away
doeth commit adultery." So, the only
reason you could put away your wife is
if she [snorts]
cheat on you. Other than that,
you not shouldn't be looking to put away
your wife.
And if you got that mind to put away,
let's go to somewhere else. Let's go to
Malachi 2.
And pick it up at verse 1. Malachi 2,
read verses 1 and 2.
Malachi 2,
verses 1 and 2 say, "And now, O ye
priests, this commandment is for you.
If ye will not hear, and if ye will not
lay it to heart to give glory unto my
name, saith the Lord of hosts, I will
even send a curse upon you, and I will
curse your blessings. Yea, I have cursed
them already because ye do not lay it to
heart." Now, skip down and read verses
13 through 16. Go ahead.
"And this have ye done again, covering
the altar of the Lord with tears, with
weeping, and with crying out, insomuch
that he regardeth not the offering
anymore, or receiveth it with goodwill
at your hand." Cuz you come into the
Lord with tears
at the altar,
but look at what you doing. Go ahead.
"Yet ye say, Wherefore?
Because the Lord hath been witness
between thee and the wife of thy youth,
against whom thou has dealt
treacherously.
Yet is she thy companion and the wife of
thy covenant. Mhm. Go ahead.
And did not he make one?
Yet had he the residue of the spirit and
wherefore one?
That he might seek a godly seed. Go
ahead.
>> Therefore, take heed to your spirit and
let none deal treacherously against the
wife of his youth. Go ahead. For the
Lord, the God of Israel, saith that he
hated putting away.
For one covereth violence with his
garment, saith the Lord of hosts.
Therefore, take heed to your spirit that
ye deal not treacherously.
So, if you got a mind to deal
treacherously with the wife that you are
married to,
think again.
Think again.
That is a covenant that God made.
Now,
you can also go to 1 Corinthians 7, read
10 to 15 on your own.
But
that is God's covenant. If you married,
you stuck like Chuck.
Unless she committed fornication. That's
all I got.
Yes, sir.
All right, brother. Thank you for that.
Good explanation on the covenant of
marriage. All right, we're going to move
on. Sister Deborah, is it new territory
time? Uh yes, we are now into tonight's
Q&A for Wednesday, April the 22nd,
2026.
PWWITV
asks, "Where in the Old Testament does
it say that the Messiah who have who
have to be
who have to be sacrificed and then rise
from the dead? So, again, where in the
Old Testament
does it say that the Messiah who have to
be sacrificed and then rise from the
dead?"
All right, so the Old Testament, Genesis
to Malachi,
where does it talk about the Messiah
would have to be sacrificed and then
rise from the dead? And let's open this
up to the panel.
You can read it about it in Isaiah 53.
There you go, right there. All right,
let's go there.
Let's go to that Isaiah 53.
You want verse 5, brother Joyce?
You you pick it up at 4 and then read it
all the way through.
Okay.
Isaiah 53 and 4 says, "Surely he hath
borne our griefs and carried our
sorrows, yet we did esteem him stricken,
smitten of God and afflicted.
But he was wounded for our
transgressions. He was bruised for our
iniquities.
The chastisement of our peace was upon
him and with his stripes we are healed.
All we like sheep have gone astray. We
have turned everyone to his own way.
And the Lord hath laid on him the
iniquity of us all. Mhm. Skip down to
verse 10.
Yet it pleased the Lord to bruise him.
He hath put him to grief. When thou
shall make his soul an offering for sin,
he shall see a seed, he shall prolong
his days and the pleasure of the Lord
shall prosper in his hand. Yeah, cuz he
going to raise him. He rose He rose from
the dead, didn't he? Mhm. Yes, sir. Go
ahead.
He shall see of the travail of his soul
and he shall be satisfied. By his
knowledge shall my righteous servant
justify many. For he shall bear their
iniquities.
>> Mhm.
Therefore, will I divide him a portion
with the great. He got to be around in
order for you to divide a portion to
him. He got to be raised from the dead
so you can give him that portion. Go
ahead.
And he shall divide the spoil with the
strong.
Because he hath poured out his soul unto
death and he has numbered he was
numbered with the transgressors
and he bear the sin of many and made
intercession for the transgressors.
Yeah.
That's all I got on it.
All right.
We'll leave it there. Thank you for that
as we move on to our next one.
Our next one, name E1K asks, "Are you
talking about the 10 kings in prophecy
or the actual European Union today?
Because the EU currently has 27
countries."
All right. Why don't we open that up to
the panel also about the EU and the
27 countries which we know some are
strong and some are considered weak.
The whole whole thing is
you got the 10 nation
Yep.
>> of the Roman Roman Empire.
And the whole thing is all of them that
have followed the European Union have to
sign one treaty.
And that is the Treaty of Rome.
Mhm. And only 10 nations I know that
have signed it.
Now, that you can research yourself. But
they will be running all of Western
Europe.
And they will have a maximum of 31
armies under their control.
Mhm.
But it's going to be 10 and that 10 is
going to turn around and yield their
power
to one man.
Yep. As far Yep. the union is Western
Europe is concerned, look under European
Union. They're going to bind up the 10.
Mhm.
They signed the Treaty of Rome.
Yep.
All right.
Thank you for that.
Hopefully that answered your question as
we move on to our next one.
Next one, A Brush With Christ says, "In
1 Corinthians 11:15
it states, 'But if a woman have has long
hair, it is a glory to her. For her hair
is given her for a covering.' My
question is, since my hair is long,
according to the scripture,
I don't have to cover my head during
holy convocations?"
Nope, that's false. You still got to
cover your head even with your
nice long hair. Let's go to that 1
Corinthians 11
that's in question.
And let's pick it up, brother, and go
open it up to the panel. Let's start at
that verse 4
about the men with their head covered
and then the woman
with her head.
Good.
Every man praying or prophesying having
his head covered dishonoreth his head.
But every woman that prayeth or
prophesieth with her head uncovered dis
dishonoreth her head.
For that is even all one if she were
shaven.
For if the woman be not covered,
uh-huh.
Hold it there.
You know, this is this is a question
that simply don't make sense.
Mhm. If the hair was the woman's
head covering, then why would the
subject even be brought up?
Yeah. Why you going to have to have your
head covered if the hair was the head?
He just used that as an example.
But any person with a reasonable mind
would say, "Why is Paul talking about a
woman
to have a head cover when the hair is a
cover?"
If it was, then he wouldn't even mention
it, would he?
Exactly.
So,
that's a question that
that I uh I don't see I don't think was
really thought out. That's all I have to
say.
All right.
And we'll uh
we'll leave it there and we'll we'll
move on to our next one.
Our next one,
uh Humanity Over Humility asks, "On the
feast days, are we required to stay and
feast after the lesson?"
On the feast days, are you required to
stay afterwards and feast after the
lesson?
Let's open that up also. Guest caller,
you got some on that.
No, there ain't no scripture that say
you required. Lord but the Lord said
what you supposed to feast.
Mhm.
Yep. So, Nope.
who you can uh uh uh uh
uh sit there and eat nothing.
But the book tell you you have to have a
holy convocation.
Mhm. I mean,
you got to come [clears throat]
together.
Whether you eat or not,
that's on you. But you have to have a
holy convocation.
But the Lord tell you to feast before
it.
So, I have to say.
All
We're going to leave that one there,
too, Deborah. Next one.
All right, next one. My Quali says, "Can
you please explain Mark 7:19?
I have a family member who needs to hear
this from the panel."
Mark 7
and verse 19.
Yes.
All right. He talking about meat here.
Let's go there. Mark 7 and verse 19.
Let's go there.
And let's pick it up at that verse 18,
James, and open that up also to the
panel.
Okay. Mark 7 and verse 18. Go ahead.
And he saith unto them,
"Are ye so without understanding also?
Do ye not perceive that whatsoever thing
from without entereth into the man, it
cannot defile him?
Because it entereth not into his heart,
but into the belly, and goeth out into
the draught, purging all meats."
Well, the first thing is
he used that to say that you can eat
anything.
Now, why would Jesus contradict himself
being that it was Jesus that gave the
dietary law? Go to first Corinthians
chapter and start reading at verse one.
See who it was.
He said first Corinthians 10
Start at verse one. Okay. It says,
"Moreover, brethren, I would not that ye
should be ignorant how that all our
fathers were under the cloud, and all
passed through the sea, and were all
baptized unto Moses in the cloud and in
the sea, and did eat all did all eat the
same spiritual meat, and did all drink
the same spiritual drink. For they drank
of that spiritual rock that followed
them, and that rock was Christ."
Well, that mean that was that was that
was Jesus back there.
Isn't that correct?
Correct.
>> Correct.
Go to the 11th chapter of Leviticus and
see uh uh who gave the 10 Commandments
uh who gave the dietary law.
11 and 1.
Okay.
11 and 1 says, "And the Lord spake unto
Moses and to Aaron, saying unto them,
Speak unto the children of Israel,
saying, These are the beasts which ye
shall eat among all the beasts that are
on the earth.
Whosoever parteth the hoof and is
cloven-footed and cheweth the cud among
the beasts, that shall ye eat.
Read a little more.
Nevertheless, these shall ye not eat of
them that cheweth the cud or them that
divide divide the hoof, as the camel,
because he cheweth the cud, but divideth
not the hoof. He is unclean unto you.
And the coney, because he cheweth the
cud, but divideth not the hoof, he is
unclean unto you.
And the hare, because he cheweth the
cud, but divideth not the hoof, he is
unclean to you.
And the swine, though he divideth the
hoof and be cloven-footed, yet he
cheweth not the cud, he is unclean to
you.
Now, so now, you cannot eat them even
with the fish with the fins and scales.
Now, the Lord is the one that separated.
I think it's in in 11:20 where he said
these are the beasts that I have
separated.
Yes, sir. Yes, sir. I think it's 11.
Yeah. Yes, and it
uh
where he talks about where he said,
"This is the law of the beasts and of
the fowl
to make a difference between the unclean
and the clean?"
What defiles you?
Yeah, that's verse 31.
Or it says, "These are un- These are
unclean to you among all that creep.
Whosoever doeth toucheth them when they
be dead shall be unclean until the
evening.
And there's another "You shall not
defile yourself with creeping things
that do creep, which I have
separated from you."
Somebody find it right quick.
Yes.
I have separated as as clean and unclean
to you.
Leviticus Leviticus 20
No, that's Leviticus 20 and 26.
20 and 26. Go ahead. Let me just read
that. Isaiah I mean, I'm sorry.
Leviticus 20 and 26
20 and 26 says, "And ye shall be holy
unto me, for I the Lord am holy and have
severed you from other people that ye
should be mine.
No, we talking
>> 25 25 Okay.
Okay.
Ye 25 says, "Yea, it says, Ye shall
therefore put difference between clean
beasts and unclean, and between unclean
fowls and clean. And ye shall not make
your souls abominable by beast or by
fowl or by any manner of living thing
that creepeth on the ground which I have
separated from you as unclean.
So now,
that's God's talking. So, what God is it
that you should not do it which he have
separated from you?
Was that the Father or was that Jesus?
It was Jesus.
Okay. So, it was Jesus then that was
Moses then. We read that, didn't we?
Mhm. Yeah.
Okay. Now, let's go and see where he
said I think it's was it is it Hebrews 8
and 13?
Where it said Jesus Christ is the same?
See if somebody can find that.
All right.
Let's search search mode for that. Yeah,
I think it's
13 and 8. Yeah.
Yeah.
Hebrews 13 and 8. Hebrews 13 and 8 says,
"Jesus Christ the same yesterday and
today and forever."
So now, if he's the same, that doesn't
mean he don't if he's the same, that
doesn't mean he don't change.
So now,
>> Right.
eat whatever you eat, sure, you going to
go to the washroom and you going to uh
uh divest yourself of it.
But if the Lord said you shouldn't eat
it,
then that makes it unclean because he
said it is unclean.
That's right.
Can I say something?
Go ahead. Can I Can I say something
against calling?
Let me Let me say
>> Uh all right, hold on 1 second, Julius.
Let uh Dre go first and you back him up.
Go ahead, brother Dre.
>> So, Mark 7 starts off talking about
eating with unclean hands. Yes.
>> That's what the conversation is about.
Eating with unclean hands and defiling.
Why are your disciples eat don't wash
their hands? They eating with defiled
hands. So, Jesus talked about what
defiles a man. That is one account in
Mark 17. I mean, Mark 7. That that you
talked about. But there's another
account in
Matthew 15.
And I just want you to see how this
ended. Matthew 15
Mhm.
And this is the same account. Yes.
So, let's let's read how this thing
ended here.
Mhm.
Matthew 15
>> up at Pick it up at verse 17.
Okay.
Matthew 15 and 17 says,
"Do not ye yet understand that
whatsoever entereth in at the mouth
goeth into the belly and is cast out
into the draught? Mhm. But those things
which proceed out of the mouth come
forth from the heart, and they defile
the man. Mhm.
For out of the heart proceedeth evil
thoughts, murders, adulteries,
fornications, thefts, false witness,
blasphemies.
These are the things which defile a man.
But to eat with unwashed hands defileth
not a man." He didn't say to eat with
pork eat pork, did he?
He didn't say to eat shrimp, lobster. He
said to eat with unwashed hands defile
not a man.
So, that's what that's talking about.
Yeah. All right. That's a twist of
scripture. Go ahead, Julius. I'm sorry.
And that's why
and and even without going to the to the
Mark the 7th chapter, you read it all
the way down to the 23rd chapter, it
would tell you all these things defile a
man. Has nothing to do with food.
So, when a person takes a sound bite of
one verse and make it into a doctrine,
which is what is happening in the world,
because they didn't finish reading the
verse or the chapter. They didn't finish
reading what Jesus was saying.
Yeah. Yeah, that's true.
Yeah.
And and everything you eat ends up in
the sewer eventually.
So, hey.
We'll um
leave it right there and sister Deborah,
we're going to move on to our next one.
>> [clears throat]
>> All right. Uh next question. Um
by Nick Juan says, "I came across people
online saying, God's chosen ones never
go to church.
Why do they say that?"
Uh can you repeat that question, please?
Yes. Uh
by Nick Juan says, "He came across
people online saying, God's chosen ones
never go to church."
And so, he asked, "Why do they say
that?"
Cuz they don't need the book.
What was the purpose of the synagogue?
What was the purpose of the Sabbath day?
Listen, tell them to read that to you.
There you go.
Come back to us.
Read read read
uh Hebrews 10:24 and 25.
Hebrews 10
chapter 10, verse 24 and 25 says,
"And let us consider one another,
let us consider one another to provoke
unto love and to good works, not
forsaking the assembling of ourselves
together, as the manner of some is, but
exhorting one another, and so much the
more, as you see the day approaching."
So, it say don't forsake the assembling
of yourselves. Where you going to do
that at? In your basement?
And after you do so
Go ahead, guest caller.
When Jesus shows
Go into Luke the fourth chapter.
And go down and and and read after he
got through being tried by Satan. And he
said and and he came, you know, uh uh
in the spirit of the Holy Ghost and read
that. Luke fourth chapter.
Luke 4
and um
and let's pick it up, brother, where he
returned.
Um 14th verse 14. Yeah, but read it down
to 16 cuz it'll say what he did, too. Go
ahead, brother.
Luke 4:14 says, "And Jesus returned in
the power of the Spirit into Galilee.
And there went out a fame of him through
all the region roundabout.
And he taught in their synagogues, being
glorified of all.
And he came to Nazareth,
where he had been brought up. And as his
custom was, he went into the synagogue
on the Sabbath day and stood up for to
read." Guest caller.
But another word for church. Mhm. You
know, the assembly.
It said, "As his custom was." Now, who
was more chosen than Jesus?
No, not one. Okay.
All right. That's all I got to say. And
so All right. So, yeah, and then be
careful of some of the stuff you do
listen to cuz some of their trains have
come off the track.
Yeah. All right.
We're going to move on to our next one,
sister Deborah, with a time check.
Yes, the time is 8:47.
Sister Tanisha asked, "Is there
something significant uh significant
uh about the number 14?
And Matthew 1:17
is given."
Matthew 1
and verse 17?
Yes, it's given.
And they want to know the significance
of the number
14. 14. Yes, is there a significance
with the number 14?
Let's read it, brother brother James,
Matthew 1
and 17. We're talking about the 14
generations.
Okay.
It says, "So all the generations from
Adam to David are 14 generations. And
from David unto the carrying away into
Babylon are 14 generations. And from
carrying away into Babylon unto Christ
are 14 nations. I mean, 14 generations."
So, let's open that up to the panel. Is
there some significance
dealing with
14? And we know that's 42 generations
total.
Only when it only when it applies to the
word of God for his use.
Mhm.
Otherwise, people going to get off into
numerology.
Yeah.
So, all right. We're going to take that
verse 17 at face value.
And uh we're going to uh continue to
move right on.
Moving on. Be alert asked, "Can you give
me the spiritual connection between
Pentecost and the eighth day?"
Pentecost and the eighth day? Let's open
that up to the panel. What is the
connection there?
Cuz God gave man seven days.
Yep.
And on the eighth day, he ain't man no
more. What day did Jesus rise?
He rose on the seventh on the seventh
day. On the seventh day.
And the eighth day
he was gone.
Yeah, all power.
Now, when the Lord tell you
that when you reap the harvest
get a sheaf of the harvest and wave
before the Lord.
He says, "Start on on the on the day
that you start, count seven Sabbath.
And tomorrow after the Sabbath,
then you wave them before the Lord
on the
eighth day."
Mhm.
Pentecost come on the eighth day.
So,
that is the day Both of them is the day
when the Lord's creation will be
presented to him.
Let's go into uh
uh let's look at the uh 1 Corinthians
the 15th chapter
where it's talking about uh uh
every man in his own order. Jesus the
first fruit and those that are his. All
right, this time.
>> And then it said, "Then come at the
end." Called Jesus.
The uh 1,000 years end on the seventh
day.
So, let's start it where it said, "And
then come at the end."
Verse 24. Yeah.
Mhm.
1 Corinthians 15:24 says, "Then come at
the end, when he shall have delivered up
the kingdom to God, even the Father.
When he shall have put down all rule and
all authority and power."
For he must Mhm.
Go finish it.
For he must reign till he have put all
enemies under his feet.
The last enemy that
The last enemy that shall be destroyed
is death.
Uh keep reading.
For he had put all things under his
feet. But when he saith all things are
put under him, it is manifest that he is
accepted which did put all things under
him.
And when all things shall be subdued
unto him, then shall shall the son of
the son also himself be subject unto him
that put all things under him, that God
may be all in all."
So now, Jesus going to have to reign and
man and and
and at the end of the seventh day, he
going to turn it over to God.
Because then he will deliver up the
creation to God. I think one of the
places you can go is I think it's
Ezekiel 44.
Ezekiel 43. Ezekiel 43.
Where where he said purge everything and
on the eighth day, you'll be accepted.
That's Ezekiel 43:26 and 27.
Read it.
Okay. Ezekiel 43:26
and 27 says, "Seven days shall they
purge the altar and purify it. And they
shall consecrate themselves. And when
these days are expired, it shall be that
upon the eighth day and so forward, the
priest shall make your burnt offerings
upon the altar and your peace offerings,
and I will accept you, saith the Lord
God."
Now, didn't Jesus tell Mary not to touch
him on the first day of the week cuz he
had not ascended to the Father? Exactly.
Then after he had went and gone and come
back then, they grabbed him by the feet.
Eighth day
and Pentecost, same thing because both
of them are the first day of something
else.
And that something else is the kingdom
of God and all immortals. Yes, they all
have to say.
All right. So, there you have the
significance.
All right.
Let's go into our next question.
Uh next one. Shanquilla
uh um
Shanqula Cole Joby says, "I understand
Sabbath is for rest and focusing on
God's word without work.
Would making a PowerPoint about God's
word for my children or creating an
online post be considered works?"
Well, that's the Lord's work.
Yeah, you can do the Lord's work on the
Sabbath day.
Cuz when you get up and teach that Bible
from the rostrum, that is work, but it's
the Lord's work. And it is written
It is written that the Lord said, you
know, Jesus told us said if the priest,
uh,
defile the Sabbath
and are blameless.
As long as you're doing the Lord's work.
Mhm. So, that's what you're doing. Don't
call it work.
All right. And since the devil time is
ticking as we are coming down on our
last couple of questions, the next one,
please. Next one, Jennifer Love asks
asks you to explain the role of a
Pharisees and Sadducees.
And she asks, "Are they Israelites?"
Let's open that up. Pharisees and
Sadducees, are they Israelites?
Yes.
>> Every one of them.
Every last one.
And what was their role?
And the Pharisees and Sadducees?
Pharisees
and the Sadducees, all of them was
Levites.
They were priests, but the problem is
somewhere along the line
the the Phar- the Sadducees didn't
believe in the resurrection.
Yeah, angels, either.
Uh-uh.
But they was Levites, but that's why
when you go and look, you see the one at
least one of the high priests was
Sadducees.
But they were the priests.
Yeah.
All right.
Hope that answered your question. Next
one.
Uh, Be Alert asks, "In Daniel 9:27,
who is this prince and why are they
called a prince?"
That's the Romans.
All right. Daniel 9, let's go there. 27,
Julius, uh,
after my brother read that, go right
ahead. 9 and 27. Daniel 9 and 27 says,
"And he shall confirm the covenant with
many for one week. And in the midst of
the week, he shall cause the sacrifice
and the oblation to cease. And for the
overspreading of abominations, he shall
make it desolate, even until the
consummation, and that determined shall
be poured upon the desolate."
Okay, first,
you know, and and what about the what
about the people of the prince? Did you
read that? That was verse 26.
>> That's in that verse above that. Yeah,
right, James. So, I'll I'll start back
at 26.
After and after threescore and two
weeks, shall Messiah be cut off, but not
for himself. And the people of the
prince that shall come shall shall
destroy the city and the sanctuary, and
the end thereof shall be with a flood,
and until the end of the war,
desolations are determined.
I think somebody go quickly and find out
and read where it say
where Satan is called the prince of the
power there. Yeah.
Quick as you can find it and read it.
Yeah, we're in search mode for that.
Ephesians 2 and 2, I think. Yes, sir.
That's it. Read it.
Okay.
Ephesians 2 and 2 says,
"Wherein in time past you walked
according to the course of this world,
according to the prince of the power of
the air, the spirit that now worketh in
the children of disobedience."
Now, that's Satan the devil.
Now, what makes Rome the people of the
prince? Go to Revelation 13 chapter and
start reading at verse one.
Okay. Revelation 13 and verse one says,
"And I stood upon the sand of the sea
and saw a beast rise up out of the sea,
having seven heads and 10 horns. And
upon his horns, 10 crowns, and upon his
heads, the name of blasphemy."
And And the beast which I saw was like
unto a leopard, and his feet were as the
feet of a bear, and his mouth as the
mouth of a lion, and the dragon gave him
his power and his seat and great
authority.
And I saw one Mhm. And listen.
Now, where did he get his power from?
Satan the devil, right? Yes, sir.
That's the Roman Empire. That's why I
said the people of the prince because
Rome got got their power from Satan the
devil.
And 40 years after Jesus,
after Jesus had came, after he had been,
uh, uh,
you know, anointed and died and went
back to heaven, 40 years later,
Titus, a Roman general, destroyed
Jerusalem down to the ground.
Yeah. So, the priest So, the people of
the prince are the ones that destroyed
Jerusalem
in 70 AD.
That's all I have to say.
All right. And since the devil, one more
question before time has ran out.
All right.
Uh,
the last question, uh, Lovely Cole says,
"How can you build a stronger
relationship with God? I'm around
I'm around people who sin, and sometimes
I slip up."
All right. Well,
one way if you love God, keep his
commandments.
Um, open to the panel.
Yeah, understand
the wages of sin is death.
Yeah. You know what you know?
To do better, you do better. You know
the consequence of it. You don't want to
get You don't want to slip up and get
caught up in that slip up and die in
that slip up.
Yeah.
That's true. And Matthew's And in
Matthew's 19th chapter, when the young
man asked Jesus, "What should he do to
keep you get you turn to life?" He told
him to keep the commandments. Keep the
commandments.
>> That's what he
No matter what they do around you, you
keep the commandments. That's all I have
to say.
Yes, sir.
All right. Sister Deborah, time check.
Uh, the time is 9:01.
9:01. Well, we have come to the end of
our program. And we like to thank
everybody all around the world who
joined us, and we say that if you
submitted a question and we didn't get
it to it, please don't resubmit it.
Sister Deborah will take it, put it in
rotation, and we will deal with that
question next week.
So, we want to thank you all once again,
and we want to say until we all come
together again, please be safe, be
blessed, stay prayed up, and may the
Lord have mercy on us all as Brother
James closes us out.
Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread, and
forgive us our debts as we forgive our
debtors. And lead us not into
temptation, but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom and the power
and the glory forever. In Jesus' name we
pray. Amen.
Amen. Amen.